A Guide to the Civil Appointments of the Virginia Governor's Office, 1780-1824
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Civil Appointments of the Virginia Governor's Office, 1780-1853
The Library of Virginia
50323
8.1 cubic feet (18 boxes)
Virginia Office of the Governor
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available.
Historical Information
The Constitution of 1776 allowed the Governor and Council of State to appoint local officials and militia officers on recommendation from county courts.
Scope and Content
Civil appointments, 1780-1853 (bulk 1780-1826), are housed in 18 boxes and include recommendations, returns, requests for remission of fines, and miscellaneous records. Includes several counties that are now located in Kentucky and West Virginia.
Series I. Recommendations, 1780-1826, are housed in 14 boxes and are arranged alphabetically by locality. This series consists of recommendations from county courts to the Governor and Council for appointments to various locality offices, as well as returns for justices. The majority of recommendations are for individuals to fill the positions of sheriff, commissioner of the peace, justice of the peace, and magistrate, though recommendations for coroner, escheator, inspector of tobacco, jailor, and surveyor are also included. The returns provide lists of commissioners/justices of the peace/magistrates and were provided to the Governor and Council upon request. These lists often cover current and previous office holders and may note those who have died, removed to other locations or failed to qualify. This series may also include correspondence, memorials, petitions, and remonstrances related to appointments; resignations; and original commissions. Also infrequently includes recommendations for militia officers. Folders for 1787 often include lists of items taxed in the locality, such as land, enslaved individuals, horses, studs, chariot wheels, phaetons, chairs, ordinary licenses, and physicians, with totals for each item.
Series II. Miscellaneous records, 1782-1853, are housed in 1 box and are arranged alphabetically by locality, if known, and then alphabetically by record type. This series is comprised of a disparate grouping of material found within the Civil Appointments collection, that includes certificates, commissions, correspondence, court martial proceedings, petitions, requests, returns, statements and other types of records. Some topics include the militia, pensions, prisoners, and defense of the western frontier.
Series III. Requests for remission of fines, 1783-1800, include petitions, accounts, correspondence, depositions and judgments related to the imposition of fines. The majority of the petitions are from sheriffs for damages for failure to collect taxes, but there are also petitions from coroners and commissioners of the revenue. Also includes a few requests from individuals to dismiss fines for retailing liquor without a license, operating a tavern without a license, and failing to appear for jury duty, as well requests from militia members for fines for failure to muster.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into three series: Series I. Recommendations, 1780-1826; Miscellaneous, 1782-1853; Series III. Requests for remission of fines, 1783-1800.
Contents List
- Recommendations, 1779-1826.
  - Accomack County, 1780, 1782-1789. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accomack County, 1793-1794, 1797-1801, 1803, 1811, 1817. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albemarle County, 1781, 1783, 1785-1789. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albemarle County, 1790-1794, 1796-1799. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Albemarle County, 1800-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1824. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amelia County, 1781-1782, 1784-1792. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amelia County, 1794, 1796-1799, 1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1824. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Amherst County, 1782, 1784, 1786-1794. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Amherst County, 1796-1798, 1800-1801, 1803-1804, 1811-1812. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Augusta County, 1781-1788, 1790-1794. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Augusta County, 1796-1801, 1818, 1829. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bath County, 1791-1799, 1801, 1803-1804, 1811. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bedford County, 1781-1783, 1785-1792. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bedford County, 1798-1801, 1803, 1806, 1811, 1818-1819, 1823-1824. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Berkeley County, 1781-1788, 1790-1791, 1793-1794. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Berkeley County, 1795-1801, 1803-1804, 1811. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Botetourt County, 1780-1791. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Botetourt County, 1793-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1819, 1823. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bourbon County, 1787-1791. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brooke County, 1796-1799, 1801, 1803, 1809, 1811-1812, 1823-1824. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brunswick County, 1781, 1784-1785, 1787, 1789-1794. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brunswick County, 1797-1801, 1803-1804, 1819. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Buckingham County, 1780-1794. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Buckingham County, 1797, 1799-1801, 1803, 1808, 1812, 1816, 1817, 1824. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cabell County, 1811, 1817, 1823. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Campbell County, 1782-1783, 1785-1787, 1789-1793. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Campbell County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811-1812. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Caroline County, 1781-1785, 1787-1794. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Caroline County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1816, 1819. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Charles City County, 1780-1782, 1784, 1786-1788, 1790-1793. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Charles City County, 1794-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1812, 1814-1815, 1824. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Charlotte County, 1783, 1785-1788, 1790-1791, 1793-1794. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Charlotte County, 1796-1801, 1803, 1806, 1811, 1812, 1817. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chesterfield County, 1781-1787, 1790-1794. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chesterfield County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1817, 1823. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Culpeper County, 1781-1784, 1786-1789, 1790-1795. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Culpeper County, 11796, 1798-1801, 1804, 1812, 1817, 1819. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cumberland County, 1782-1796. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cumberland County, 1797-1801, 1803-1804, 1811, 1823-1824. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dinwiddie County, 1780-1795. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dinwiddie County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1824. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Elizabeth City County, 1780, 1782-1787, 1789-1792. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth City County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Essex County, 1780-1792. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Essex County, 1793-1801, 1801, 1803-1804, 1807. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax County, 1782-1788, 1790, 1792-1794. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax County, 1796-1800, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax County, 1814, 1816, 1823-1824. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fauquier County, 1781-1783, 1785, 1787, 1789, 1791-1794. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fauquier County, 1796-1797, 1799-1800, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fayette County, 1781-1789, 1791. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fluvanna County, 1780-1789, 1791-1793. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fluvanna County, 1796-1801, 1804, 1811-1812. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Franklin County, 1784, 1786-1794. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Franklin County, 1797, 1799-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Frederick County, 1782-1790, 1792-1794. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Frederick County, 1797-1799, 1801, 1803-1806, 1811, 1813, 1824. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Giles County, 1819, 1824. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gloucester County, 1781-1782, 1784-1791, 1793. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Gloucester County, 1794, 1797-1801, 1804, 1811, 1816. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Goochland County, 1782-1790, 1792. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Goochland County, 1794, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1811-1812. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Grayson County, 1793-1794, 1796-1801, 1803, 1806, 1811, 1824. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Greenbrier County, 1782-1784, 1786-1792. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Greenbrier County, 1793-1794, 1796-1799, 1801, 1803-1804, 1807, 1811-1812, 1816. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Greensville County, 1783-1787, 1789, 1791-1792. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Greensville County, 1794-1795, 1797-1801, 1803-1804. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Halifax County, 1780-1782, 1784-1787, 1789-1795. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Halifax County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811-1812, 1822-1824. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Hampshire County, 1782-1784, 1786-1790, 1794-1795. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hampshire County, 1797-1801, 1803-1804, 1808, 1811, 1823. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hanover County, 1782-1788, 1790, 1792-1794. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hanover County, 1796, 1798, 1800-1801, 1803-1806, 1811-1812. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hardy County, 1785-1788, 1790-1794. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Hardy County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1811, 1816, 1819. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Harrison County, 1784-1796. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Harrison County, 1797-1801, 1803, 1815-1817, 1823. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Henrico County, 1782-1789. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Henrico County, 1791-1794, 1796-1801, 1803, 1806. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Henry County, 1782-1783, 1785-1787, 1789-1791. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Henry County, 1793-1794, 1796-1797, 1799-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811-1812. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Isle of Wight County, 1783-1785, 1787-1788, 1791-1794. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Isle of Wight County, 1796-1801, 1804, 1809, 1816, 1818-1819, 1823. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - James City County, 1781-1790. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - James City County, 1792, 1794-1801, 1804, 1806, 1823. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jefferson County, 1782-1788, 1790, 1800-1801, 1803, 1806, 1811, 1819. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kanawha County, 1790, 1792, 1794-1795, 1797, 1799-1801, 1803-1804, 1808, 1811-1812, 1817, 1819, 1824. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - King and Queen County, 1783-1794. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - King and Queen County, 1796-1801, 1803-1805, 1811-1812, 1823. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - King George County, 1780-1782, 1784-1785, 1787, 1789, 1791-1794. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - King George County, 1795-1801, 1804, 1811-1812, 1824. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - King William County, 1781-1782, 1784, 1786-1788. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - King William County, 1790-1792, 1794, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811-1812, 1817-1818. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Lancaster County, 1781-1788, 1790, 1792-1794. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lancaster County, 1797-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1814, 1824. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Lee County, 1793-1794, 1796, 1798-1799, 1801, 1803, 1810-1812, 1815. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Lewis County, 1817, 1819, 1823. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln County, 1781, 1783-1790. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Loudoun County, 1779, 1781, 1783, 1785-1787, 1789, 1791-1795. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Loudoun County, 1797-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1824. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Louisa County, 1781-1788. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Louisa County, 1790, 1792-1794, 1796-1800, 1803-1805. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lunenburg County, 1781, 1785-1788, 1790-1794. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lunenburg County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1809, 1811-1812. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Madison County (KY), 1786-1789. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Madison County, 1793-1794, 1798, 18011-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811-1812. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Mason County, 1788-1790, 1804, 1806-1807. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Mathews County, 1790-1799, 1801, 1803-1804, 1806-1807, 1823. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Mecklenburg County, 1781-1782, 1784-1786, 1788-1792. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Mecklenburg County, 1793-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1823. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Mercer County, 1785-1786, 1788-1791. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Middlesex County, 1780, 1782-1789, 1790-1792. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Middlesex County, 1793-1795, 1797, 1799, 1801, 1803, 1806, 1811-1812, 1817. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Monongalia County, 1781-1785, 1787-1788, 1790, 1792, 1794. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Monongalia County, 1796-1800, 1803-1804, 1810, 1816, 1819, 1822-1824. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Monroe County, 1799-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1816, 1818. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Montgomery County, 1782-1787, 1790-1791, 1793-1796. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Montgomery County, 1797-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1817-1818, 1824. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Nansemond County, 1780, 1782, 1784-1789, 1790, 1792-1795. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Nansemond County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1811, 1824. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Nelson County, 1784, 1786-1791, 1794, 1797, 1799, 1811-1812. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - New Kent County, 1780, 1782-1788, 1790-1794. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - New Kent County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1808, 1811-1812, 1819, 1823. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Nicholas County, 1823. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Norfolk County, 1782-1792. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Norfolk County, 1793-1794, 1796-1800, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Northampton County, 1781, 1783, 1785-1789, 1791. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Northampton County, 1793-1795, 1797, 1799-1801, 1806, 1811, 1818, 1823. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Northumberland County, 1781-1795. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Northumberland County, 1796-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811-1812, 1816, 1819, 1823. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Nottoway County, 1789-1794, 1796-1801, 1803-1804. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ohio County, 1782, 1784-1785, 1787, 1789, 1791-1794. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Ohio County, 1796-1800, 1803-1804, 1806, 1818. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Orange County, 1781-1782, 1784-1788, 1790-1792. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Orange County, 171794-1796, 1798-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1818. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Patrick County, 1791, 1793, 1795, 1797-1801, 1803, 1806, 1811, 1817-1818. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Pendleton County, 1788-1791, 1793-1801, 1804, 1806, 1811, 1816. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Pittsylvania County, 1781, 1783-1790. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Pittsylvania County, 1792-1797, 1799-1801, 1803-1804, 1811. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Pocahontas County, 1824. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Powhatan County, 1781-1783, 1785-1789, 1791, 1794-1795, 1799-1801, 1803, 1806, 1811-1812. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Preston County, 1819. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Prince Edward County, 1781-1791. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Prince Edward County, 1793-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1809, 1811-1812, 1816. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Prince George County, 1781-1787, 1789-1794. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Prince George County, 1795-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1813. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Prince William County, 1781-1790. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Prince William County, 1791, 1793-1794, 1796-1798, 1800-1801, 1803-1804, 1806. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Princess Anne County, 1781-1783, 1785-1788, 1790-1791. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Princess Anne County, 1793-1796, 1799-1801, 1803-1804, 1817. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Randolph County, 1786-1796. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Randolph County, 1797-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1823. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Rappahannock County, 1801. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Richmond County, 1782-1794. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Richmond County, 1795-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811-1812, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Rockbridge County, 1781-1791. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Rockbridge County, 1793-1801, 1804, 1806, 1811-1812. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Rockingham County, 1781-1791. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Rockingham County, 1793-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1810-1811, 1817, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Russell County, 1786-1789, 1793-1794, 1796-1801, 1803, 1806, 1811. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Scott County, 1817, 1819, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Shenandoah County, 1781, 1783-1791. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Shenandoah County, 1793, 1795, 1797-1799, 1801-1803, 1806, 1811, 1816, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Southampton County, 1781-1791. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Southampton County, 1793-1801, 1803-1804, 1807, 1811, 1814, 1816. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Spotsylvania County, 1781-1788, 1790-1794. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Spotsylvania County, 1795-1796, 1798-1801, 1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Stafford County, 1780-1783, 1785-1789, 1791-1793. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Stafford County, 1794-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1817-1818, 1823. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Surry County, 1782-1783, 1785-1790, 1792-1793. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Surry County, 1794-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Sussex County, 1782-1788, 1791-1793. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Sussex County, 1794-1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Tazewell County, 1800, 1803-1804, 1806, 1811, 1818. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Tyler County, 1816. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Warwick County, 1782-1788, 1790, 1792-1794. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Warwick County, 1795, 1797-1801, 1803, 1811-1812, 1816. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Washington County, 1780-1782, 1784-1788, 1791-1794. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Washington County, 1796, 1798, 1801, 1803-1804, 1806, 1816, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Westmoreland County, 1780-1783, 1786-1792, 1794. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Westmoreland County, 1795-1801, 1803-1806, 1812, 1818-1819, 1823. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Wood County, 1800-1801, 1803-1806, 1818-1819, 1823. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Woodford County, 1789-1790. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Wythe County, 1791, 1793-1794, 1798-1799, 1803, 1806, 1824. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - York County, 1782-1790, 1792-1793. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - York County, 1794-1796, 1798-1799, 1801, 1803, 1806, 1816-1817, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Alexandria, 1796. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Fredericksburg, 1784, 1787, 1796-1799, 1801, 1803. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Lynchburg, 1812. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Norfolk Borough, 1787, 1789, 1791-1792, 1794-1796, 1798-1801, 1803-1804, 1823. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Petersburg, 1803, 1811. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Richmond, 1787, 1794, 1796. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Williamsburg, 1783, 1787. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Winchester, 1787, 1794. (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous records, 1782-1853.
  - Accomack County - Statement of the number of suits standing on the docket, 178-1784. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Amelia County - On the subject of Henry Anderson's property, 1792. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Botetourt County - Petition of James McCarrol regarding the whipping of a boy, undated. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Campbell County - Commissioners of the Lynchburg Warehouses v. Benjamin Arthur, 1799. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth City County - Return of sundry people who did not pay their specific tax, 1782. (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Frederick County - Escheator's certificate for Robert Page (Attorney for Commonwealth v. Thomas Bryan Martin), 1799. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Fredericksburg - Request of Inspectors of Tobacco for blank tobacco notes, 1803. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Halifax County - Payment to Capt. Michael Roberts for repair to the jail, undated. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Henrico County - Ommission of Mrs. Mary McCarty from the pension list, 1800. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Lancaster County - Petition of Thomas Myers regarding runaway slaves, 1801. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Lincoln County / Fayette County - Correspondence of Levi Todd regarding laws to provide against indian invasion, 1785. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Louisa County - List of property taken to discharge taxes, 1786. (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Mecklenburg County - Allowance for Capt. Joseph B. Clausel for removing arms, 1812. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Mecklenburg County - Petition of Abraham Keen regarding a dispute involving the Sheriff's Office, 1818. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Monongalia County - Escape of prisoner (Thomas Wilson alias Smith), 1799. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Montgomery County - Escape of prisoners (John Wash and John Bullis), 1799. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Ohio County - Petition in favor of Israel McDonough, a convict in the Penitentiary, 1801. (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Pittsylvania County - Pardon request for Hampton, a negro man, undated. (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Prince Edward County - Application for arms (Capt. Purnall), 1799. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Richmond City - Application of Gershom Patton for award for apprehending Thomas Burnett, 1798. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Richmond City - Correspondence of Allyn Prior, 1799. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Rockbridge County - Report of a review of a way for a road from Botetourt, 1793. (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Russell County - Certification of John Gilbert as acting administrator for the estate of Joseph Gilbert, 1794. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Staunton - Return of the number of revised codes furnished to the court, 1812. (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Williamsburg - Court of Directors of the Hospital for the maintenance and cure of persons of unsound mind / Lunatic Hospital, 1798, 1801, 1803. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Wythe County / Montgomery County - Sheriff appointment, 1804. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Adjutant General - Circular regarding return of arms, undated. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Application for advance of money for Dr. Brand, 1794. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Assistant Clerk of the Council (Samuel Coleman) regarding receipts for tobacco, 1791. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Certificate of John Schwartz for delivery of two decanters of wine to Freeman Jordan, 1799. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Court martial proceedings of Capt. Joseph Wiseger, 1795. (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Court martial proceedings of John Fox, undated. (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Court martial prcceedings of Thomas Clarke, 1799. (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Defense of the Western Frontier, 1788-1790. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Defense of the Western Frontier - List of warrants by the Auditor since 26 July last, 1791 Dec 31. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Defense of the Western Frontier - Statements of expenses (Bourbon, Fayette, Greenbrier, Harrison, Jefferson, Lincoln, Madison, Mercer, Monongalia, Montgomer, Nelson, Ohio, Randolph, Russell), 1788-1791. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Militia Commission of Calvin S. Simmons, 1853. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Militia payments (Botetourt, Franklin, Greenbrier, Kanawha), 1793-1795. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Proposition of Thomas Vaughan to be appointed collector of the arrears of the revenue tax for several counties, 1796. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Regarding the pension of Alexander McFarlin, 1797. (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Regarding James Martin, a prisoner in the penitentiary, from son Daniel Martin, 1801. (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Request from the Land Office for plank floors, 1796. (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Returns of representatives and delegates, 1801. (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Unidentified, undated. (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Requests for remission of fines, 1783-1800.
  - Accomack County, 1786. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Albemarle County, 1785-1786, 1789, 1798-1799. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Amelia County, 1783-1785, 1787, 1797-1799. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Amherst County, 1786, 1791, 1793, 1796-1797, 1800. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Augusta County, 1785, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Bath County, 1798-1799. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Bedford County, 1796-1797. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley County, 1787, 1791, 1794, 1798. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Botetourt County, 1796, 1800. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Brooke County, 1797, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Brunswick County, 1783-1785, 1796, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Buckingham County, 1792. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Campbell County, 1797. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Caroline County, 1786, 1791, 1797. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Chesterfield County, 1791, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Culpeper County, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Cumberland County, 1785, 1790, 1797-1798. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Dinwiddie County, 1785-1786, 1794, 1796, 1798-1799. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Elizabeth City County, 1785, 1796, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Essex County, 1796. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Fairfax County, 1791, 1793, 1797, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Fauquier County, 1783, 1790, 1795, 1797-1799. (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Fluvanna County, 1791. (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Franklin County, 1792. (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Frederick County, 1791, 1798-1799. (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Gloucester County, 1783, 1787, 1796, 1799. (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Goochland County, 1785, 1788, 1791, 1796, 1798-1799. (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Greenbrier County, 1798. (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Halifax County, 1787, 1790, 1793. (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Hampshire County, 1786, 1796-1799. (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Hanover County, 1796-1799. (Box 17, Folder 1)